<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bismuthcoin.org – Dapp</title><link>https://bismuthcoin.org/tags/dapp/</link><description>Recent content in Dapp on bismuthcoin.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bismuthcoin.org/tags/dapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tesla Battery Monitoring</title><link>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-05-25-tesla-battery-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-05-25-tesla-battery-monitoring/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-battery-monitoring.webp" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
Tesla is a market leader in electric vehicles (EVs). They have currently sold and delivered more than 1 million EVs worldwide while production is ramping up fast with new factories in Europe and China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tesla Battery Monitoring on Blockchain&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="tesla-battery-monitoring-on-blockchain"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;a href="#tesla-battery-monitoring-on-blockchain" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although EVs in general require little maintenance, one expensive component in the car needs to be treated with care: the battery. This video explains what can happen if it is not. With Tesla EVs, there is an 8-year warranty on the battery. After this period of time, there is no longer a warranty, but a car is normally expected to last much longer than this. Although battery costs are declining over time, a replacement battery would typically cost $10,000 or more nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what can an owner do to maximize the lifetime of his or her EV battery? The CEO of Tesla – Elon Musk – has previously recommended to keep the battery level between 80% and 30%, see this tweet and the reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-tweet.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below illustrates that the lifetime of Li-Ion batteries is limited to a number of charging cycles. As seen from the table, smaller charging cycles consume proportionally less lifetime compared with full charges. The typical lifetime of a Li-Ion battery with 0-100% charge cycles is typically 450 cycles. With 10% charge cycles, on the other hand, the lifetime would typically be 10,000 cycles or more. So, a battery with 10% charging cycles will typically achieve a double lifetime compared to one which has done 0-100% cycles, for the same kWh energy consumption. It is clear from this observation that the charging behavior of the owner will significantly influence the condition of the battery, and hence the potential resale value of the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Li-cycle-life.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
Table from the paper: Yu Miao et.al., “Current Li-Ion Battery Technologies in Electric Vehicles and Opportunities for Advancements”, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/en12061074" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/en12061074&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When selling an EV on the second hand market, the remaining lifetime of the battery should be one of the most important questions. However, this question could be quite difficult to answer. If the battery condition is unknown, this could affect the resale value by giving the owner a lower price regardless of the actual condition. If, on the other hand the owner can prove, somehow, that the battery was treated with care and the expected amount of remaining lifetime is significant, the resale value of the vehicle should naturally be higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Tesla screen inside the vehicle and also on Tesla’s phone app, it is possible to view and inspect some battery parameters. However, these parameters are lost over time. There is a plot in the car which shows the efficiency (Wh/mi or Wh/km), but this plot is limited to the last few miles or kilometers. After a certain distance those values are lost for the owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla has an (unofficial) API which allows 3rd party services to log data from owner’s cars. However, by using these services you have to either expose your Tesla login credentials or give an API token to these services. Many owners do not feel comfortable doing this, because it means the 3rd party service could potentially take control over your car, not just read data. Also, there is no guarantee that a 3rd party web service will continue to exist over the lifetime of your car. The average lifetime of an app or a web service is usually considerably shorter than a vehicle. If the operator of the service decides to discontinue – for whatever reason – your vehicle data may be lost. Even if you have a backup of the data, this may not be very useful if the user interface to display and analyze the data is no longer available. Another factor is the cost: most of the 3rd party services require you to pay a monthly fee to use their service to display and analyze your own historic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where blockchain technology enters the picture. The article &lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-04-30-condition-monitoring/" &gt;“Decentralized Condition Monitoring”&lt;/a&gt; explains how a public blockchain can be a good solution when the following conditions are met:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than one participant needs to be able to submit and update data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The participants do not need to know and trust each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data does not need to be private.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The database needs to be resistant to attacks or censorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the above-mentioned reasons a solution for battery condition monitoring of Tesla EVs has been implemented by using the open source Bismuth public blockchain. Specifically, a Tesla plug-in (also called “crystal” in Bismuth terminology) has been developed for use together with the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/bismuthfoundation/TornadoWallet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;TornadoWallet&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the features of the implemented solution are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The vehicle owner will not expose his or her login credentials to anyone, since the app runs on the local computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the code involved is open source and publicly available on GitHub on the official account of the Bismuth Foundation. Hence, anyone can verify that the software is safe to use and that there is no malicious intent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the owner submits data from the vehicle to the public blockchain, he or she can decide to publish the vehicle’s identification number (VIN) openly, or to encrypt it with a password to remain anonymous. This should ideally be a strong password, and not identical to an existing one used for other apps or services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the owner wants to sell the vehicle in the future, the password can be revealed to the new owner. The new owner can then verify that the submitted data actually belongs to the vehicle’s VIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first owner can transfer the virtual asset on the blockchain to the new owner, to allow the new owner to continue to submit data from the vehicle using his or her own account, while keeping the entire track record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To discourage spam and fake data, there are some costs (fees in BIS currency) involved when registering a new VIN on the chain and to submit data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone submits fake data to the chain, this would most likely be detected by other users, or by new data analysis services based on the publicly available data. For example, the odometer of a car can never decrease, or the amount of energy (kWh) added should, to some extent, match the battery level and distance driven parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To view and analyze the data is free for everyone. A public website has been set up for this purpose, to allow anyone to view and analyze the data without owning a Tesla vehicle or the need to run the TornadoWallet on their local computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public website has been developed to also work well with the Tesla in-car browser (Chromium). The screenshots below are taken from an actual vehicle, for both Night and Day mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-01.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
viewed in a Tesla vehicle (Night Mode).
&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-02.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
viewed in a Tesla vehicle (Day Mode).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an Android phone it is also possible to run the Tesla plug-in locally by using Termux, &lt;a href="https://steinbuch.wordpress.com/2015/01/24/tesla-model-s-battery-degradation-data" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;see link&lt;/a&gt;. In this way, it is possible to submit vehicle data while on the road, for example just before and after charging your vehicle at a public supercharger station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screenshot below shows the data viewing and analysis section of the app. In this example, the vehicle IDs available for viewing have been encrypted with a password. Hence the actual VIN numbers of these cars are not available. The address on the right shows which Bismuth account has submitted the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-03.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the menu above, a vehicle asset ID is selected as well as the start and end dates. After that, a number of parameters are available for viewing and analysis. One example plot is the “Estimated Max Range vs. Odometer” and the associated curve fit, see plot below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-04.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
Estimated Range vs. Odometer and Curve Fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The green dots in this plot represent individual data points submitted by the owner to the blockchain. The parameter “Estimated Max Range” is based on data from the Tesla API, by dividing the estimated remaining range with the battery level. The curve fit is based on the data points matching the “Range Filter”. In this example only the 1% largest values are used to estimate the red curve. As can be seen from this plot, the estimated max range is falling, from about 485km to 480km. However, this plot does not necessarily represent the true battery condition, since a number of parameters may influence the estimate, such as ambient temperature, driving style, road conditions, etc. The way to get a more accurate measure of maximum range is to do a full charge (0-100%) and then check the EPA rated range (in North America) or Typical range (in Europe and Asia/Pacific), see link. However, you don’t want to do this exercise too often, as a 0-100% deep charging cycle is exactly what reduces the remaining lifetime of the battery the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the owner submits data to the blockchain regularly, just before and after every charging event, it is instead possible to estimate the battery life without having to do deep charges. If all the charging events are recorded, Bismuth’s Tesla app allows for counting the cycles, using a method called rainflow counting, as illustrated in the screenshots below. The rainflow method is normally used in counting fatigue cycles in mechanical engineering, but it can also be used for counting battery cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-05.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-06.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
Counted battery cycles and “Full Cycle Equivalent” during a selected time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot above shows that the owner has made several charging cycles at various levels from 10% up to 100%. By using the Li-Ion cycle life table from Miao et.al, these charging events are converted and summed up to a “Full Cycle Equivalent” of 6.03 during the time period selected (May 2020). Since the battery is expected to have a life time of about 450 full cycles, it can be estimated that 1.3% of the battery life was used up during this particular month. If this owner charges the equivalent of 6 full cycles every month, this battery can be expected to last about 77 months, or 6.5 years – significantly less than the normal expected lifetime of a car. Hence, by using the developed app, an owner can monitor the battery lifetime consumption of the vehicle on a daily, weekly or monthly basis, without performing harmful 0-100% deep charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there is talk about new batteries which will be capable of “a million miles” and a much higher number of charging cycles. In the paper by Harlow et.al, “&lt;a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1149/2.0981913jes" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;A Wide Range of Testing Results on an Excellent Lithium-Ion Cell Chemistry to be used as Benchmarks for New Battery Technologies&lt;/a&gt;” (2019) batteries with NMC532 cathodes have been found capable of higher cycle life, of 5000 or more deep charges. However, it is currently being speculated that such batteries will be used in vehicles connected to the grid (V2G), which means that deep charges could potentially happen much more frequently, perhaps even on a daily basis (charge at night when power prices are low, and sell during the day when prices are high). In such scenarios it could be of even larger importance to record the charging cycles to document remaining lifetime and ensure as high a resale value of the vehicle as possible. If and when V2G becomes a reality, the Bismuth team will make available automated data to blockchain submission scripts to capture high-frequency charging events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-07.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Bismuth’s Tesla app, PDF files can also be generated for selected dates to document, for example, total distance driven during a given period or the sum of charge energy (kWh) added. In the example above, the sum of charge energy added is found to be 131.13kWh, since there are only three actual charging events (58.49, 51.18 and 21.46 kWh) in the submitted data. Such reports could for example follow the car when sold, as an alternative to giving away the password for the asset id on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining two screenshots below are only available in the local app, and not on the public website. The first screenshot shows the asset registration screen. Here, the Tesla credentials are entered (username and password) as well as a (strong) anonymizer password if the user does not want to expose the actual VIN number. When the asset id has been registered, it will be linked to the Bismuth wallet address by paying a small fee. Only data for this asset id submitted from this account will be visible on the public website and in the plotting and analytics section of the app. If the owner later wants to transfer the vehicle to another owner, it must first be unregistered on the chain which allows the new owner to register it. By using the same password as the previous owner the original data set for the vehicle can be continued by the new owner. If a different password is used, then the asset id will be different and a new data set will be started from scratch. The Tesla credentials (username and password) will always stay on the local computer, and are never exposed to any external websites or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By entering the Tesla credentials and the anonymizer password (if any), battery data is collected from the vehicle. Once the data has been collected, it can be submitted to the Bismuth blockchain by paying a small fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-25-Tesla-Bismuth-Crystal-09.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
Screen for fetching battery data using the Tesla API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bismuth crypto currency is required to pay for fees and can be purchased on one of the BIS &lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/exchanges" &gt;exchanges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help and support is given in our &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/4tB3pYJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; There is a dedicated channel named #batterylife.&lt;br&gt;
For those who are not able to run from the source code, updated binaries for Windows, Mac and Linux are available at our &lt;a href="https://github.com/bismuthfoundation/TornadoWallet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="references"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;a href="#references" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/en12061074" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Current Li-Ion Battery Technologies in Electric Vehicles and Opportunities for Advancements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1149/2.0981913jes" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Benchmarks for New Battery Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/echanges" &gt;BIS Exchanges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/4tB3pYJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Bismuth Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Android Battery Monitoring</title><link>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-05-09-battery-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-05-09-battery-monitoring/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-09/battery.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;
The Android operating system is installed in about 70% of mobile phones worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of these phones are using Lithium-Ion (Li-ion) battery cells. Li-ion batteries are relatively expensive. To make sure that the battery lasts as long as possible, below are some tips to achieve that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Li-ion chemistry prefers partial discharge to deep discharge, so it is best to avoid taking the battery all the way down to zero. Since Li-ion chemistry does not have a memory, the battery pack is not harmed with a partial discharge. If the voltage of a lithium-ion cell drops below a certain level, it is ruined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Li-ion batteries age and only last a few years, even if they are sitting on a shelf unused. So do not avoid using the battery with the thought that the battery pack will last longer. It will not. Also, if you are buying a new battery pack, you want to make sure it really is new. If it has been sitting on a shelf in the store for a year, it will not last as long as a brand new pack. Manufacturing dates are important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid heat, which degrades the battery. If the battery gets hot enough to ignite the electrolyte, there will be a fire, usually caused by an internal short.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;strong&gt;decentralized distributed app&lt;/strong&gt; (dApp) has been developed with the aim of monitoring battery parameters, such as temperature, charging current, battery level and health status. The dApp uses the Bismuth public blockchain to store battery data, and makes use of a second layer asset protocol, see &lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-04-30-condition-monitoring/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Condition Monitoring Link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phone battery monitoring dApp serves several purposes, some of which are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collect enough publicly available data to allow and encourage development and verification of battery analytics algorithms,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow a user to monitor the performance of his/her mobile phone battery and to enable condition monitoring and hopefully early detection of abnormal performance, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to record an immutable performance record of an asset (the mobile phone battery), with the potential to increase future resale value. For example, if a user records on the blockchain the battery data before and after every charging event, the number of battery cycles can then be counted and estimated remaining lifetime potentially calculated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dApp has a public website available at &lt;code&gt;https://phone.batterylife.info&lt;/code&gt;. At this site it is possible to search for and view performance data of different mobile phone batteries, submitted by users around the world. The submitted data can be linked to the serial number of the phone. This serial number can be submitted as is, or encrypted with a password to allow anonymous sharing of data. The encryption uses the password and the asset id as input to a sha256 hash, which guarantees anonymity. Later, if desired, the ownership of the asset can be proven by performing the hash calculation based on the password and the asset id again and comparing the result with the hash stored on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public website allows for plotting of variables such as battery temperature, charging or discharging current and battery level. PDF reports can be generated and saved for individual mobile phones. Later, when more data has been submitted by a larger number of users, the data analysis section of the dApp will be expanded. The Bismuth project has several discussion channels on Discord and interested users submitting battery data could potentially discuss battery performance and warn each other if abnormal performance is detected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to submit data to the public blockchain, it is necessary to run the Tornado wallet on the Android phone itself using Termux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructions for how to install the Tornado wallet on Termux can be found here:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2019-04-14-termux/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2019-04-14-termux/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the instructions given, the Termux API must also be installed in order to collect battery data from the phone. Termux API can be installed with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="hextra-code-block hx-relative hx-mt-6 first:hx-mt-0 hx-group/code"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pkg install termux-api&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class="hextra-code-copy-btn-container hx-opacity-0 hx-transition group-hover/code:hx-opacity-100 hx-flex hx-gap-1 hx-absolute hx-m-[11px] hx-right-0 hx-top-0"&gt;
&lt;button
class="hextra-code-copy-btn hx-group/copybtn hx-transition-all active:hx-opacity-50 hx-bg-primary-700/5 hx-border hx-border-black/5 hx-text-gray-600 hover:hx-text-gray-900 hx-rounded-md hx-p-1.5 dark:hx-bg-primary-300/10 dark:hx-border-white/10 dark:hx-text-gray-400 dark:hover:hx-text-gray-50"
title="Copy code"
&gt;
&lt;div class="copy-icon group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-hidden hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="success-icon hx-hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-block hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To submit mobile phone battery data to the Bismuth blockchain, activate the crystal named Phonebattery. A screenshot of the main menu of this crystal is shown below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-09/battery-02.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that as a safety feature, the Tornado Wallet needs to be restarted after a crystal has been activated. In this case, press CTRL+C in Termux to stop the wallet and restart it again with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="hextra-code-block hx-relative hx-mt-6 first:hx-mt-0 hx-group/code"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/TornadoWallet/wallet; python wallet.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class="hextra-code-copy-btn-container hx-opacity-0 hx-transition group-hover/code:hx-opacity-100 hx-flex hx-gap-1 hx-absolute hx-m-[11px] hx-right-0 hx-top-0"&gt;
&lt;button
class="hextra-code-copy-btn hx-group/copybtn hx-transition-all active:hx-opacity-50 hx-bg-primary-700/5 hx-border hx-border-black/5 hx-text-gray-600 hover:hx-text-gray-900 hx-rounded-md hx-p-1.5 dark:hx-bg-primary-300/10 dark:hx-border-white/10 dark:hx-text-gray-400 dark:hover:hx-text-gray-50"
title="Copy code"
&gt;
&lt;div class="copy-icon group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-hidden hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="success-icon hx-hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-block hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top button in the menu above (Analyze Phone Data) leads to a screen which is identical to the one on the public website, &lt;a href="https://phone.batterylife.info" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://phone.batterylife.info&lt;/a&gt;. The other two menu items (Register Phone and Fetch Phone Data) are only available in the crystal and will only work when run using Termux on an Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screenshot below shows the plot and DataTable for one specific Android phone, generated using the public website. In the “Select ID” field different Android phones can be selected. The IDs displayed here are either the asset number of the phone, or the asset number encrypted with an anonymizer password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-09/battery-03.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example of public website display for a particular Android phone asset id.
Data from individual phones can be exported to either PDF or CSV for further offline analysis. The screenshot below shows an example of a generated PDF file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2020-05-09/battery-04.png" alt="" loading="lazy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that it costs 5 BIS to register a phone to participate in the data displayed in the crystal and at the public website. In addition, it costs 1 BIS for every submission of a new data transaction from the phone. These fees are mainly introduced to reduce spam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIS can be purchased on a number of exchanges, listed at &lt;a href="https://coinpaprika.com/coin/bis-bismuth/#!exchanges" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Coinpaprika&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any income generated by the paid fees will be used to reward new developers who would like to participate in further development of the dApp. The Tornado wallet itself and the Phone Battery crystal are both open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of all the available crystals is available at the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bismuthfoundation/TornadoWallet/tree/master/wallet/crystals" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Github Tornado Wallet Repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; link explains how to get started with crystal development for the Tornado wallet:
&lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-04-13-hello-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-04-13-hello-world/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pull Requests can be used by anyone who is interested in contributing to the source code of the Bismuth Foundation, see for example:
&lt;a href="http://oss-watch.ac.uk/resources/pullrequest" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;http://oss-watch.ac.uk/resources/pullrequest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="references"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;a href="#references" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Termux Android: &lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2019-04-14-termux/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Termux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coinpaprika Exchanges: &lt;a href="https://coinpaprika.com/coin/bis-bismuth/#!exchanges" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Coinpaprika&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello World App: &lt;a href="https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-04-13-hello-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull Request: &lt;a href="http://oss-watch.ac.uk/resources/pullrequest" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Pull Request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>