<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bismuthcoin.org – Exchange</title><link>https://bismuthcoin.org/tags/exchange/</link><description>Recent content in Exchange on bismuthcoin.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bismuthcoin.org/tags/exchange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bismuth has been Listed on XeggeX Exchange</title><link>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2024-03-02-exchange-listing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2024-03-02-exchange-listing/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2024-03-02/exchange-listing.webp" alt="" loading="lazy" />
The Bismuth Foundation has some fantastic news to share!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bismuth cryptocurrency has been listed on XeggeX, a leading exchange ranked within the top 50 globally at CoinGecko. This is a significant milestone for us and an excellent opportunity for Bismuth’s growth and visibility in the market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>XeggeX has earned a high trust score of 8 on CoinGecko, an achievement to its credibility and reliability in the cryptocurrency community. An important aspect of XeggeX is its transparency, as evidenced by their public disclosure of reserve data. This aligns well with our values of trust and integrity in all our operations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those unfamiliar, XeggeX.com operates as a centralized exchange and is renowned for its focus on cryptocurrencies with low to medium market capitalization. A notable feature of XeggeX is its no-KYC (Know Your Customer) requirement, making it accessible and user-friendly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CoinMarketCap recently added XeggeX as a new exchange, marking its entry into the rankings and signaling growing recognition in the industry. Its position is expected to improve over time, especially since XeggeX supports reserve data, which has not yet been reflected in its current standing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This listing serves as an important step forward, showcasing the relentless commitment and hard work of our team. It opens new doors for Bismuth and brings us closer to our goal of making digital currency accessible and usable for all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s celebrate this achievement and continue to push the boundaries of what we can accomplish together!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Continuing our exciting announcement about Bismuth’s listing on XeggeX, I’d like to take a moment to reflect on our journey so far and look ahead to our promising future with XeggeX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bismuth has indeed experienced its share of challenges and fluctuations over the years. We all remember the difficulties faced by the community, especially during the prolonged periods of price decline. It’s been a journey of resilience and learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In its early days, Bismuth gained significant traction thanks to Cryptopia. This exchange played a crucial role in increasing our trading volume, boosting our price, and enhancing our overall market presence. However, the sudden closure of Cryptopia was a setback for us. Subsequently, qTrade stepped in to list Bismuth. We’re incredibly grateful for the excellent service and technical prowess demonstrated by qTrade during our partnership. Despite their exceptional service, qTrade’s overall market reach and trading volume did not match that of Cryptopia, and eventually, they too ceased operations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we continue to celebrate Bismuth’s listing on XeggeX, it’s important to acknowledge the challenges we faced in finding a suitable replacement for qTrade. This search was neither quick nor easy, but it was a journey marked by dedication and community spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We owe a special thanks to a valued member of our community, ‘sgaragagghu’, whose insightful suggestion led us to discover XeggeX. This instance is a powerful testament to the vital role our community plays in our project’s success. It’s a clear demonstration of how collaboration and contributions from each member can significantly impact our collective journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This experience has reinforced the importance of our community’s voice and involvement. Your insights, suggestions, and feedback are not just welcomed but are integral to our progress and success. As we embark on this new chapter with XeggeX, let’s remember that our strength lies in our unity and collective effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, as we partner with XeggeX, we’re entering a new chapter. XeggeX might have a smaller trading volume compared to other top 50 exchanges. — their current 24-hour trading volume stands at ca. $3 Million — but their monthly website user visits are impressively higher than some exchanges with greater trading volumes. This is a promising indicator for Bismuth’s potential growth and visibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>XeggeX offers a robust platform with established trading services, and we believe this will be a golden opportunity for Bismuth to regain recognition in the cryptocurrency market. We encourage everyone to familiarize themselves with XeggeX — understand their processes for depositing, withdrawing funds, and trading cryptocurrencies. This knowledge will be indispensable as we move forward in this exciting new phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together, we can continue to navigate challenges and seize opportunities, further solidifying Bismuth’s position in the cryptocurrency world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>References&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="references">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#references" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Xeggex &lt;a href="https://xeggex.com/post/new_listing_bismuth_bis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">listing announcement&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Xeggex exchange &lt;a href="https://xeggex.com/market/BIS_USDT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BIS-USDT trading pair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Xeggex exchange &lt;a href="https://xeggex.com/market/BIS_LTC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BIS-LTC trading pair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The largest ignored use case for cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-05-30-cryptocurrency/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bismuthcoin.org/blog/2020-05-30-cryptocurrency/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://bismuthcoin.org/images/2025-03-26/bismuth-crypto.png" alt="" loading="lazy" />
Cryptocurrencies and trading. They are indivisible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since your first purchase of Bitcoin to your potential cashing out, be it for fiat or for products and services, &lt;strong>you have to deal with trading&lt;/strong>. Considering the volatile nature of crypto, you are also most likely to be introduced to technicalities surrounding it – walls, spreads, supports, resistances, formations, trends, the list is endless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is often surprising, however, how divided the worlds of crypto traders and exchanges versus crypto developers and dedicated followers are. They seem to skip the most evident reality of crypto for ideology. But we should not ignore trading. We should take advantage of this most important use case there is, because there is no skipping it. It will always be here, and always be a major part. At least until Bitcoin surpasses fiat currencies as a world standard – the idealists “are already there”, &lt;strong>ignoring all the opportunities surrounding it&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The realization of importance of trading led me to the programming of &lt;a href="https://github.com/hclivess/qtrader" target="_blank" rel="noopener">qTrader&lt;/a>, an interface which actively trades on one of the best crypto exchanges around, &lt;a href="https://qtrade.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">qTrade&lt;/a>. It is a simple bot designed for &lt;strong>automated trading&lt;/strong>, it just places sell orders and buy orders on top of bid and ask sides, guaranteeing you best current prices for selling and purchasing your favorite projects. It is configurable for both distribution and accumulation. There it started. I entered the rabbit hole of algorithmic trading from a more active position than before. Suddenly, I was no longer just a fascinated consumer of other people’s bots. I was one of the authors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My fascination led me onto &lt;a href="https://www.freqtrade.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Freqtrade&lt;/a>, which is far more versatile and dynamic tool than qTrader. It is completely free and you can import your favorite trading strategies based on technical analysis into it. It runs on two main pillars, &lt;a href="https://github.com/mrjbq7/ta-lib" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TA-Lib&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ccxt/ccxt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CCXT&lt;/a>. I thought to myself: I clearly see what qTrader is missing as compared to Freqtrade. But what does qTrader have that Freqtrade does not? Then it struck me. It was the integration of the qTrade exchange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From there, I contacted Eric from qTrade, who already previously talked to the CCXT team. With the CCXT team focusing on their own development and problems, the integration was pushed down on the priority list. Eric, however, said he would talk to the CCXT team again and he did. They promised they would add qTrade within 14 days and that’s what happened. Therefore, you will soon be able to trade there using Freqtrade. &lt;strong>Code merging&lt;/strong> happened on &lt;strong>Monday, May 25&lt;/strong>. After that, some testing might still be required to see if everything works as intended.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freqtrade offers you a bundle of basic and more advanced trading strategies, which you can further adjust and customize using Python and the TA-Lib, which is a technical analysis trading library. Most of the hard stuff has already been written, you just need to configure your conditions for buying and selling based on indicators. Or you can try the bundled ones – moving averages, bollinger bands, scalping. You can backtest your strategy and preview its performance in the so called “dry run” before you’re ready to put your money to task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am continuing with research into algorithmic trading and thinking about &lt;strong>more ways on how to make Bismuth useful in this regard apart from it just being a traded cryptocurrency&lt;/strong>. There could be services offering algorithmic trading that would incur minimal fees and would use Bismuth for purchase of individual plans. If we were capable of improving the existing strategies or developing our own with better profitability, this use case would &lt;strong>open a door to an entirely new level of crypto adoption&lt;/strong>. Because everyone in crypto trades crypto, whether they like it or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jan Kučera
Team Bismuth&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>References&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="references">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#references" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/hclivess/qtrader" target="_blank" rel="noopener">qTrader&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://qtrade.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">qTrade&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.freqtrade.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Freqtrade&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/mrjbq7/ta-lib" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TA-Lib&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/ccxt/ccxt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CCXT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>